<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>X86 SBC on Industrial sbc</title><link>https://industrial-sbc.com/tags/x86-sbc/</link><description>Recent content in X86 SBC on Industrial sbc</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://industrial-sbc.com/tags/x86-sbc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ARM vs x86: What’s Best for Industrial SBCs?</title><link>https://industrial-sbc.com/articles/arm-sbc-vs-x86-sbc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://industrial-sbc.com/articles/arm-sbc-vs-x86-sbc/</guid><description>&lt;p>Choosing the right processor architecture for an &lt;strong>industrial single-board computer (SBC)&lt;/strong> is one of the most important technical and business decisions in any embedded project. The choice between &lt;strong>ARM&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>x86&lt;/strong> is not just about processor speed—it affects everything from thermal design and power budgets to software development, maintenance, and long-term supply. In industrial environments, where products may need to operate continuously for a decade or more, the architecture you choose will directly influence system reliability, development costs, and your ability to adapt to future requirements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intel vs AMD Embedded Boards: Performance, Power, Price</title><link>https://industrial-sbc.com/articles/intel-vs-amd-embedded-boards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://industrial-sbc.com/articles/intel-vs-amd-embedded-boards/</guid><description>&lt;p>When it comes to choosing an &lt;strong>embedded x86 board&lt;/strong> for industrial applications, the decision often narrows down to &lt;strong>Intel&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>AMD&lt;/strong>. Both companies have decades of experience in CPU design, mature product lines tailored for embedded computing, and long-term supply commitments. But while they share the x86 instruction set and many architectural similarities, their embedded product offerings differ significantly in &lt;strong>performance characteristics, power efficiency, cost structure, and ecosystem support&lt;/strong>. These differences have practical implications for developers building industrial PCs, single-board computers (SBCs), and edge AI systems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Power Consumption Comparison: x86 vs ARM in Fanless Industrial SBCs</title><link>https://industrial-sbc.com/articles/power-consumption-comparison-x86-vs-arm-in-fanless-industrial-sbcs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://industrial-sbc.com/articles/power-consumption-comparison-x86-vs-arm-in-fanless-industrial-sbcs/</guid><description>&lt;p>When it comes to &lt;strong>fanless industrial SBCs&lt;/strong> (Single Board Computers), power consumption is one of the most critical design considerations. Fanless designs rely on passive cooling, meaning every extra watt of heat generated must be dissipated through heatsinks and chassis design without the help of active airflow. This makes &lt;strong>CPU architecture choice—x86 or ARM—especially important&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In industrial environments, where 24/7 operation, reliability, and environmental constraints matter, the power efficiency of the SBC determines not only thermal stability but also &lt;strong>longevity, maintenance requirements, and operating costs&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Selecting the Right Architecture for Embedded AI (ARM vs x86)</title><link>https://industrial-sbc.com/articles/selecting-the-right-architecture-for-embedded-ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://industrial-sbc.com/articles/selecting-the-right-architecture-for-embedded-ai/</guid><description>&lt;p>The demand for &lt;strong>embedded AI&lt;/strong> is growing rapidly, driven by applications like smart manufacturing, autonomous vehicles, medical diagnostics, and intelligent security systems. At the heart of any embedded AI system is the &lt;strong>processor architecture&lt;/strong>, and two major contenders dominate the market: &lt;strong>ARM&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>x86&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choosing the right architecture for your AI project can be challenging. The decision impacts &lt;strong>performance, power consumption, thermal design, cost, and even software compatibility&lt;/strong>. In this guide, we explore the strengths and weaknesses of ARM and x86 for &lt;strong>AI at the edge&lt;/strong>, so you can make an informed decision.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>